<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cmd.Io on Glider Labs, Open Source Innovation Lab</title>
    <link>http://gliderlabs.com/tags/cmd/index.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cmd.Io on Glider Labs, Open Source Innovation Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gliderlabs.com/tags/cmd.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Commands as a Service with Cmd.io</title>
      <link>http://gliderlabs.com/devlog/2016/announcing-cmd-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gliderlabs.com/devlog/2016/announcing-cmd-io/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce a soon-to-be-released, eventually open source
product for developers, operators, and power users. It&amp;rsquo;s called Cmd.io, or
&amp;ldquo;Command IO&amp;rdquo; as we pronounce it. Cmd.io will let you use and share commands for
the terminal, as a service, over SSH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Cmd.io you can make or install command-line utilities that you can use
from anyplace with an SSH client. Commands are run in a consistent environment
that you configure specifically for you or your team. You can share access to
your commands, allowing friends and colleagues to run them as well. This is
great for letting anybody on your team kick off build or deployment automations
right from their terminal. But this is only the beginning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the demo video below, we use &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt; as a service, build a PDF with LaTeX
without installing it, provision cloud resources using
Terraform with no configuration or credentials, and
turn &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; into a powerful, programmable automation tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;ui embed&#34; data-source=&#34;vimeo&#34; data-id=&#34;181089646&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://gliderlabs.com/devlog/2016/quiet-accomplishments-gliderlabs-v1/&#34;&gt;last
post&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ll be &amp;ldquo;rebooting&amp;rdquo;
Glider Labs this month to focus on a number of innovative tools like this. More
on that soon. We just couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to give you a preview of what&amp;rsquo;s to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re excited by Cmd.io you can subscribe with the link below to hear when it&amp;rsquo;s
available and possibly get early access. Otherwise,
let me know what you think in the comments, including ideas you might have for
how you&amp;rsquo;d use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;ui info message&#34;&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;mail icon&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eepurl.com/cdWjaX&#34;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;
  to be notified when Cmd.io comes online.

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
